<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Stuff Bernard Likes</title><link href="http://granitosaur.us/likes/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://granitosaur.us/likes/feeds/all-en.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://granitosaur.us/likes/</id><updated>2020-07-18T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Dinosaurs</title><link href="http://granitosaur.us/likes/dinosaurs.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-18T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-07-18T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Bernard</name></author><id>tag:granitosaur.us,2020-07-18:/likes/dinosaurs.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ever since I was a kid I always liked Dinosaurs, well I guess most kids do! As an adult I just really like the idea behind dinosaurs — this ancient creatures that are long gone and we have this space to speculate and imagine how they looked and behaved!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I don't get to enjoy dinosaurs that much in real life; actually I could hardly name any. However I admire the idea behind them and aesthetically they are very pleasing!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been playing this game called "Jurassic World Alive" and it's a GPS based game where you go around and catch various dinosaurs and finally have them fight each other. It's a fun time waster and quite educational as well as I finally managed to learn few dinosaur names  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure which dinosaur is my favorite. It used to be some sort of raptor when I was a kid but now I'm quite fond of weird looking chill stegosauruses and such.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category><category term="animal"></category><category term="nature"></category></entry><entry><title>Manga</title><link href="http://granitosaur.us/likes/manga.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-18T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-07-18T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Bernard</name></author><id>tag:granitosaur.us,2020-07-18:/likes/manga.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I don't read comics often but there are so many absolute gems in japanese comic medium. It seems that comic artists have so much freedom in expressing their ideas and while western comics are all about supernatural, manga often covers a lot of niche subjects like mundane tasks like cooking or historic dramas.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some of my favorite works are by these two artists:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Naoki Urasawa - brilliant mystery thriller author. His characters never fail to come to life and stories always keep you at the edge of the seat. My favorites are Monster, 20th Century Boys and Pluto.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Junji Ito - horror manga super star. His art and ideas are often so peculiar and weird that I'm constantly in awe how he manages to make it work. My favorite story is about a town cursed with spirals that drives everyone crazy — it's very lovecraftian! &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category><category term="books"></category><category term="hobbies"></category><category term="reading"></category><category term="japan"></category></entry><entry><title>Matcha Tea</title><link href="http://granitosaur.us/likes/matcha-tea.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-18T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-07-18T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Bernard</name></author><id>tag:granitosaur.us,2020-07-18:/likes/matcha-tea.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I adore the taste of this tea and even more so I really appreciate the traditional preparation process. It's really relaxing ceremony!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Match is traditional japanese green tea powder tea. The taste is quite unique, some people say it's often a bit fishy but it's definitely an acquired taste!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went ahead and got myself a set and so far I've been making myself a cup or two every day for the past few weeks! It has been such a relaxing experience and you can see my first attempt here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bGNhx49iX40" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category><category term="food"></category><category term="drinks"></category></entry><entry><title>Outrun</title><link href="http://granitosaur.us/likes/outrun.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-18T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-07-18T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Bernard</name></author><id>tag:granitosaur.us,2020-07-18:/likes/outrun.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love 80s Neon aesthetic and deep synthetic sounds. I already mentioned that I like Vaporwave and while similar outrun is a different take. While Vaporwave is often mellow and nostalgic, outrun feels opposite of the same coin: active and nostalgic.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Outrun appears in many different forms though mainly in visuals and music and I'm very fond of both! Visual are sharp, optimistic and bright which provides this energetic but slightly dark futuristic look. I've been listening to a lot of outrun music while working. It gives me a bit of boost though occasionally it might get away in focus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has been my favorite spotify playlist so far:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/playlist/5IUxvS0U3ZL2NwKoybYEmD" width="300" height="380" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true" allow="encrypted-media"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point I'd really like to open neon-themed café that would either be outrun or vaporwave inspired and I could never find anything like this.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category><category term="music"></category><category term="genre"></category><category term="art"></category><category term="style"></category></entry><entry><title>Photography</title><link href="http://granitosaur.us/likes/photography.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-02-28T05:13:18+01:00</published><updated>2020-02-28T05:13:18+01:00</updated><author><name>Bernard</name></author><id>tag:granitosaur.us,2020-02-28:/likes/photography.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Photography is a fun, accessible and pragmatic art medium. New phones come with brilliant cameras and it's so easy to always be ready for some cool shots - and there are so many!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure what sort of photography I enjoy the most. I like abstract and nature photos though my nature shots tend to be quite average, abstract and artsy stuff feels more of my thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been thinking of starting a photography blog but I still have a lot to learn. Recently though I've been studying Darktable program a lot which definitely helped to improve my photography game!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://pixelfed.social/Wraptile/embed" class="pixelfed__embed" style="max-width: 100%; border: 0" width="400" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;script async defer src="https://pixelfed.social/embed.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category><category term="photography"></category><category term="activity"></category><category term="hobbies"></category></entry><entry><title>Zdislav Beksinski</title><link href="http://granitosaur.us/likes/zdislav-beksinski.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-02-25T14:59:24+01:00</published><updated>2020-02-25T14:59:24+01:00</updated><author><name>Bernard</name></author><id>tag:granitosaur.us,2020-02-25:/likes/zdislav-beksinski.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A brilliant artist that is often considered to be the father for horror surrealism!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After world war 2 Poland, understandably so, started to produce some of the most interesting artists in whole wide world. Even though Beksinski didn't want his art to be interpreted you can definitely see lots of ww2 influences. This weird mix of ww2 horrors and modernity of new world brought us some of the first surreal horror paintings and they are absolutely captivating! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's something about these deserted, haunting landscapes that focus on central colossal subjects give off this haunting and addicting feeling that is difficult to describe. That's my favorite part of Beksisnkis work!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's an album of my favorite works by Beksinski:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wikiart.org/en/profile/5e54a5acedc2c9ece862e996/albums/horror"&gt;wikiart album&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category><category term="artist"></category><category term="art"></category><category term="horror"></category><category term="painting"></category><category term="photography"></category></entry><entry><title>Sauna</title><link href="http://granitosaur.us/likes/sauna.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-02-18T12:50:52+01:00</published><updated>2020-02-18T12:50:52+01:00</updated><author><name>Bernard</name></author><id>tag:granitosaur.us,2020-02-18:/likes/sauna.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I used to heavily dislike Sauna but over time it kinda grew on me. Major enjoyment that I discovered is actually my new enjoyment in stressing my body - it weirdly feels rejuvenating!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I actually used to live in Estonia and even stayed in a house that had a sauna in it! That being said I always felt uncomfortable in one and the whole experience felt rather pointless.&lt;br&gt;
Now that I live in Thailand which is often pretty much a big sauna on it's own I discovered my enjoyment for this weird activity! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My last condo had the nicest sauna I've ever been with city view and was just such a zen place to chill at. Sitting there for 20 minutes and then jumping into cold pool was such a refreshing experience.&lt;br&gt;
My current condo also has a nice sauna and a really really cold pool that makes such a great combo!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category><category term="activity"></category><category term="health"></category></entry><entry><title>Geese</title><link href="http://granitosaur.us/likes/geese.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-02-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-02-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Bernard</name></author><id>tag:granitosaur.us,2020-02-18:/likes/geese.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Gease are probably my favorite birds. They are adorable, weird and tough!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html"></content><category term="misc"></category><category term="pet"></category><category term="animal"></category><category term="nature"></category></entry><entry><title>Rats</title><link href="http://granitosaur.us/likes/rats.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-02-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-02-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Bernard</name></author><id>tag:granitosaur.us,2020-02-17:/likes/rats.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Rats are absolutely adorable, smart and such fun creatures! I used to have 3 rats and were some of the best friends I've had!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Rats were my first independent adult pets. I've had to lady rats and they were great pets with few big caveats. First I'll start with positives: they are super cute. They would explore, chill, eat and often act very human-like except. For me they were great pets as you can have one on your lap and do some work on your laptop or read a book - if you're a house person rats can really fit into your workflow!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bad parts are that they love to chew cables and thing in general - it's a bit difficult to let them loose especially if you're having a bunch of tech lying around! &lt;br&gt;
Finally they don't live very long and are very attachable. Two of my rats died of cancer while the other died from some unknown nerve disease. They lived almost 3 years which is really good for rats but nevertheless you get really attach to them and the short lifespan is a huge turn-off. I probably don't want to have rats for this reason anymore.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category><category term="pet"></category><category term="nature"></category><category term="animal"></category></entry><entry><title>Coffee</title><link href="http://granitosaur.us/likes/coffee.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-02-16T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-02-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Bernard</name></author><id>tag:granitosaur.us,2020-02-16:/likes/coffee.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I used to dislike coffee but since I moved to Thailand I'm having it almost every day! Turns out it's such a varied drink that is part of an enjoyable preparation ritual.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's an acquired taste and it took me few years to get to it but since I've started my trip here in south-east asia I've got a taste for it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It started in Vietnam - the beautiful "phin" coffe caught my eye. The traditional coffe over there is prepared by pouring some condensed sweet milk at the bottom of the glass and putting a little filter device on top of it. The filter is being filled tight with grounded coffee beans and hot water is poured on top. It slowly drips on the milk and by the time it's done is has gently mixed with it as well as cooled down to drinkable temperature. The first sip you take is a bitter strong coffee maybe slight feel of the milk, then you mix the glass up a bit for a sweet milky relief.&lt;br&gt;
It's such a cosy procedure that really got me hooked on it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vietnamese coffee my favorite as described above is my favorite but there's much more to the coffee world than that. I like flat whites and cappuccinos when going out, while at home I usually stick with french press with a splash of sweet soy milk. Sometimes pure black coffee with a dash of palm sugar is such an empowering breakfast drink.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category><category term="food"></category><category term="drinks"></category></entry><entry><title>Lofi Hip-Hop</title><link href="http://granitosaur.us/likes/lofi-hip-hop.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-02-16T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-02-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Bernard</name></author><id>tag:granitosaur.us,2020-02-16:/likes/lofi-hip-hop.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lofi hip-hop has really been my core background music for a while now. It's relaxing and not introsive which helps me to focus on my work. Weirdly enough it also helps me feel less lonely - same effect as how people often run TV in the background.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hHW1oY26kxQ" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category><category term="music"></category><category term="genre"></category></entry><entry><title>Tea</title><link href="http://granitosaur.us/likes/tea.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-02-16T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-02-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Bernard</name></author><id>tag:granitosaur.us,2020-02-16:/likes/tea.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Herbal, green, black or red - there are just so many plants that taste great when splashed with boiling water!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've only discovered my taste for tea in my late teens. I used to think it's such a lame drink - might as well drink water but it turns out the tea medium is overwhelmingly huge. There are just so many different teas and herbal brews. Sure you can stick with good ol' green or black tea (the actual tea) but you can also explore blends. Blend some black tea with dried bergamot (basically lemon) and you've got Earl grey tea. What about orange? Berries? Some flowers? There are so many possibilities for blends!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there are herbal teas which basically are all sorts of herbs that when boiled taste either nice or influence your body in some way. My favorite of such teas is simple chamomile tea which has pleasant, creamy mild taste and sweet odor of meadows. Throw in some cumin seeds and you've got yourself a bit of a kick too!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category><category term="food"></category><category term="drinks"></category></entry><entry><title>Economy</title><link href="http://granitosaur.us/likes/economy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-02-14T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-02-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Bernard</name></author><id>tag:granitosaur.us,2020-02-14:/likes/economy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I find economy's role in our society fascinating. Majority of our lives are influenced by economic designs and decisions and yet it's not that apparent.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My interest in economy was started by Bitcoin. The idea of decentralized programmable money was really captivating. This kinda led me into the world of liberal finance and later to economy at large.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real interest started with economic book called "freakonomics". I was looking around a book shop for a graduation gift for my friend who just have graduated from business management major and I stumbled upon Freakonomics. Little did I know that it was one of the most popular recent books on economy! I got a an ebook copy on it myself and went through it. It really turned out an interesting subject and the book revealed how economy influences our lives.&lt;br&gt;
Turned out that there's a podcast too by the same author. I've been listening to Freakonomics ever since!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category><category term="hobbies"></category><category term="theory"></category><category term="concept"></category></entry><entry><title>Philosophy</title><link href="http://granitosaur.us/likes/philosophy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-02-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-02-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Bernard</name></author><id>tag:granitosaur.us,2020-02-13:/likes/philosophy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Philosophy is one of my favorite subjects to study. In general I find thinking awfully addicting to the point and the questions raised in this subjects just feeds of this weakness of mine!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When growing up I haven't been exposed to the medium of philosophy at all. We got some theology (absolute rubbish) classes that we watched harry potter movies and alternatively you could pick ethics classes which I really felt connected to but it was hard to compete with movies and in my late teens I switched to that because of peer pressure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later on I discovered a lot of philosophy through software, free/libre software to be more exact. The arguments made by libre community seemed so alien but at the same time so ratable and attractive - it made sense! Since then I've been a firm believer in this philosophy but not only that it opened up gates to a lot of other philosophical subjects from stoicism to weird niches like accelerationism!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll leave you with my favorite podscast series that introduced me to a lot of what philosophy has to offer, specifically great series on Friedrich Nietzsche made me a big fan of the false worlds concepts and how we live with them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://philosophizethis.org/god-is-dead-and-so-is/"&gt;Episode 90 – Nietzsche pt. 1 – God is Dead And So Is Captain Morgan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category><category term="hobbies"></category><category term="theory"></category><category term="concept"></category></entry><entry><title>Succulents</title><link href="http://granitosaur.us/likes/succulents.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-02-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-02-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Bernard</name></author><id>tag:granitosaur.us,2020-02-13:/likes/succulents.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Succulents are super practical and just captivating plants. They feel alien, unique and captivating while only requiring minor care - by far my favorite plants to own!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've always owned some sort of succulents, mostly cacti as they are most common. Recently when I moved to Thailand I got exposed to much higher variety of them as they are really cheap and plentiful here. My condo has a huge balcony too which can accommodate a whole jungle if I wish so!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most interesting part about succulents is that they look like they're from a different world! They seem so unatural, quirky and almost defy what we think of what plants are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've always been meaning to dig into sciency bits of succulents but for the time being they are just lovely little friends that chill with me in the balcony.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category><category term="plant"></category><category term="nature"></category></entry><entry><title>Thailand</title><link href="http://granitosaur.us/likes/thailand.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-02-02T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-02-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Bernard</name></author><id>tag:granitosaur.us,2020-02-02:/likes/thailand.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been living in Chiang Mai, Thailand for 2 years now - needless to say I love this place! It has it's faults but it has been my favorite place to stay so far!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As of right now I've been 2 years in Thailand. It has been such a lovely place to live in as a remote worker. The rent is cheap, the food is delicious, the people are lovely and there's always something to do here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are few down-sides though. It's not as developed as europe and there's rampart corruption and the smog season (February to late April) really sucks but other than that it's hard to find things to complain about!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category><category term="place"></category><category term="country"></category></entry><entry><title>Watercolor</title><link href="http://granitosaur.us/likes/watercolor.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-02-02T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-02-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Bernard</name></author><id>tag:granitosaur.us,2020-02-02:/likes/watercolor.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My favorite drawing/painting medium. Watercolor is so practical and it has this hazy psychedelic feeling as if you're drawing with clouds&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've only tried actual painting few times and really wanted to get into it to some extent but it just awfully impractical. As an alternative I've learned of watercolor and it ticks all of the right boxes! You only need thick paper, water and well - the watercolor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really fancy the style too - it quite psychedelic and flowing. I guess you could achieve similar goals with oil and acrylic paints but with watercolor it comes straight out of the box!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category><category term="hobbies"></category><category term="art"></category></entry><entry><title>Chicken</title><link href="http://granitosaur.us/likes/chicken.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Bernard</name></author><id>tag:granitosaur.us,2020-02-01:/likes/chicken.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Chicken are adorable and quite interesting! I ever have a house with a big yard I'd like to keep few.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Chicken go CHUCK CHUCK and dig around and then wag their tails. They used to be dinosaurs too!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category><category term="pet"></category><category term="animal"></category><category term="nature"></category></entry><entry><title>Doom Metal</title><link href="http://granitosaur.us/likes/doom-metal.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Bernard</name></author><id>tag:granitosaur.us,2020-02-01:/likes/doom-metal.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;By far the heaviest sort of music you can produce. I find the gloomy sound so captivating and psychedelic.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been introduced to this genre by a reddit thread - about black blues musician who discovered this music and felt real connection. That's exactly what I felt the first time I heard Electric Wizard. The first song I've heard was probably the most famous modern song: Funeropolis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/F-x6qqNy0mo" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've been somewhat interested in blues bot often I'd find it not pure or gloomy enough - doom metal scratches this itch really well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electric Wizard is my favorite doom band but there are just so many great choices in this not-so-little subgenre! Black Sabbath is the band started it all but the medium really started to become it's own thing in late 2000s and it's growing every day!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category><category term="music"></category><category term="genre"></category></entry><entry><title>Harmonica</title><link href="http://granitosaur.us/likes/harmonica.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Bernard</name></author><id>tag:granitosaur.us,2020-02-01:/likes/harmonica.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Such a practical instrument! I really enjoy the bluesy sound it produces and I got introduced by it by Cowboy Bebop animated show that featured one of the best players in the world - Wheeping Harp!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I admit the sound sometimes can be overwhelming but when played accordingly it sounds super bluesy. I very much prefer it as a solo instrument or at least as a main one as it sounds quite overwhelming - in a good way!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category><category term="music"></category><category term="tool"></category></entry><entry><title>Horror Books</title><link href="http://granitosaur.us/likes/horror-books.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Bernard</name></author><id>tag:granitosaur.us,2020-02-01:/likes/horror-books.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love scary books! Be it fairy tales, lovecraftian stories or mystery detective thrillers - the spooky supernatural is awesome!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Horror books are like fairy tales for adults. The mystery, supernatural and human conflict show up the best during stressed by duress of the unknown!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category><category term="books"></category><category term="hobbies"></category></entry><entry><title>Japan</title><link href="http://granitosaur.us/likes/japan.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Bernard</name></author><id>tag:granitosaur.us,2020-02-01:/likes/japan.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I find volcanic islands just beautiful - combine that with the charming japanese culture and you have such a pleasant environment!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've never been to Japan but would like to visit it one day. However I've been interested in the country for as long as I remember and have been learning about it ever since!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category><category term="place"></category><category term="country"></category></entry><entry><title>Origami</title><link href="http://granitosaur.us/likes/origami.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Bernard</name></author><id>tag:granitosaur.us,2020-02-01:/likes/origami.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Origami is such a practical art expression - all you need is a piece of paper and you can make an object out of it: how cool is that?&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I really enjoy Origami - thought I'm rather unskilled at it. It's a really practical art form as you only need a piece of paper. It's also really hard to get into as there are many books and youtube videos to guide you through!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first attempt is almost always a garbled flop, but that's kinda part of the fun as you can see yourself progress!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category><category term="hobbies"></category><category term="art"></category></entry><entry><title>Shrimp</title><link href="http://granitosaur.us/likes/shrimp.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Bernard</name></author><id>tag:granitosaur.us,2020-02-01:/likes/shrimp.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Domestic Neocardina shrimp are just adorable!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The first time I've got introduced to shrimp tank was in a small cosy cafe in Da Nang, Vietnam and ever since then I wanted to have one. The shrimp as just so adorable and the whole scenery is just so relaxing and calming!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of 2019 I got a small tank here in thailand. It was only 70€ and the shrimp themselves are super cheap too. We got some Dario fish too but I feel that I'd prefer the tank without them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often work at the kitchen with shrimp keeping me company - it's a very calming experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I leave you with a short timelapse I made:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zyBWDZ2jxSQ" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category><category term="pet"></category><category term="animal"></category><category term="nature"></category></entry><entry><title>Vaporwave</title><link href="http://granitosaur.us/likes/vaporwave.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Bernard</name></author><id>tag:granitosaur.us,2020-02-01:/likes/vaporwave.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Such a phenomena! I've lived through the very inception of it and the 80s super-consumer atmosphere is right up my alley.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Vaporwave is a music genre but it's bigger than that. It was such an interesting pop culture art movement that I am happy to have gone through. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grew up in the 90s and 90s Lithuania felt like 80s of the rest of the world. My first console was Sega Genesis at around 1997 to put things into perspective how behind we were. So the 80-90s capitalistic scene of vaporwave did resonate with me even though I never lived through the era american malls of the 80s. Once Lithuania picked itself up it kinda jumped through all of the fads in an accelerated time frame - shopping malls, neon colors, denim were all there but it flew by without many of us really getting to get into it. Maybe that's why I enjoy this feeling - it allows me go back a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course as music vaporwave was exactly what I like - it's was enjoyable, not taking itself too seriously but nevertheless making you think if you wanted to dig deeper. The sampling of various 80s beats, phrases and even movies or anime promoted this familiarity feeling of carelessness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally the A E S T H E T I C and meme community was absolutely top notch. I'm a fan of pastel colors and sunsets which really was the major part of vaporwave aesthetics. At some point I'd like to own a vaporwave themed cafe but by the time I get around to it the medium might be dead if it's not already :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll leave you with my favorite recent vaporwave piece and my favorite video essay on the subject:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8L6r1wm3fXk" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xJwqp0IByto" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category><category term="music"></category><category term="genre"></category><category term="art"></category><category term="style"></category></entry></feed>